(字幕: 李卓人)
我們今天的主題是
"主宰靈性的宇宙"
主宰靈性的宇宙
我們今年開始讀哪本書呢?
知道嗎?
Mark的書
如同你所見的下一個頁
我們學習了很多東西
耶穌主宰了靈性的宇宙
祂可以治癒病人
可以把人變成石頭和麵包
祂可以給予五千人
祂也是聖誕老人
上週我們學到耶穌是聖誕老人
今天我們要學到
耶穌是主宰靈性的宇宙
主宰靈性的宇宙
我們一起讀Mark 4
一起讀
1,2,3
(翻譯)
(看著畫面)
耶穌去了新的地區
很多人想祂被治癒
有些人有不潔的靈魂
我們知道聖靈有聖靈
但也有不潔的靈魂
不潔的靈魂跟祂說
You are the son of God
不潔的靈魂知道耶穌是誰
我問你們
Do you believe in the spiritual realm?
That there is unclean spirits
That there is demons, angels
誰覺得有靈魂的?
因為有靈魂的
這些女孩沒想過
只有有靈魂的
(看著畫面)
聖經說
聖經很清楚說
是有靈魂的
(看著畫面)
下一個畫面是一個回答機
有一次我小時候在彈琴
(彈琴)
有個回答機
誰以前有個回答機?
Mentors應該有吧
有人打來
你不聽電話
就自動錄音回答
Message
我彈琴的時候
我小時候像你們一樣
有個Message是這樣的
黃牧師
為什麼你不聽電話?
我像你們這個年紀
你覺得你的反應會怎樣?
這個人有什麼問題?
我爸爸回來的時候
我爸爸是牧師
他就解釋了
Johnny你還好嗎?
因為這個回答機
是我幫這個人
做Exorcism
Exorcism
所以那是我第一次
遇到靈魂的世界
我就覺得
哇!這些東西真的存在
那我就問你
你有沒有遇到靈魂的世界?
你有看過一些東西嗎?
它們可以是天使
可以是魔鬼
它們存在
撒旦、魔鬼
我問一下你們
你覺得是從哪裡來的?
這些魔鬼、不潔的靈魂
它們從哪裡來的?
有沒有人知道?
它們是人類的嗎?
你覺得它們是人類的嗎?
還有誰知道?
它們是從哪裡來的?
有沒有人知道?
這三個人是誰來的?
知道嗎?
有人知道嗎?
這個是
神創造
三頭天使
它們的名字是甚麼?
有沒有人知道?
M字頭的
Michael
有沒有人知道?
是Michael的
第一頭天使的名字是Michael
第二是G字頭的
有沒有人知道?
Gabriel
第三是甚麼名字?
是甚麼?
L字頭的
Lucifer
三頭天使
Michael
Gabriel
Lucifer
但是Lucifer
發生了甚麼事?
為甚麼神創造了他
是一個天使
發生了甚麼事?
我們看Isaiah 14
我們一起讀
準備,1,2,3
(英文)
Lucifer,神創造了他
是怎樣的?
是一個Morning Star
這裡寫
Old Day Star
很漂亮的
他是一個Beautiful
其實我不用戴口罩
他是一個Beautiful Morning Star
但是他怎樣?
他就怎樣?
他覺得他自己怎樣?
他就開始驕傲
驕傲呢?
Pride
他覺得他自己很漂亮
很偉大
I will make myself like the most high
他覺得自己可以像神一樣
This angel had pride
And what happened to him?
結果是甚麼?
Not death
He was fallen
God threw him down to the earth
To Shiloh
To the far reaches of the pit
我們看到
這個是The beginning
The start of Satan
和他的Legions
His followers
The angels that followed Lucifer
What happened to them?
They were all thrown towards the earth
這些魔鬼有甚麼能力?
他們可以做甚麼?
有沒有人記得?
這些魔鬼可以做甚麼?
首先他們可以擁有人
他們可以擁有人
如果人們給他們控制
他們可以擁有他們
並且鼓勵他們
並且造成他們的身體和靈性傷害
他們可以使他們做惡
我們可以看到
在整個福音書中
當魔鬼擁有他們
他們有超自然的能力
我沒有見過
但我聽說有些朋友
見過有人擁有魔鬼時
他有超自然的能力
超自然的能力
魔鬼可以做甚麼?
他可以盯著我們的心
保護我們從真相中
他們可以欺騙人
欺騙人
以為他們是正義的
就像反對耶穌基督
他可以欺騙人
推動謊言
魔鬼可以推動謊言
他們可以造成證據
來欺騙人
這些魔鬼是有能力的
這些不潔的靈魂
是有能力的
他們有能力
我們繼續讀
馬克四書
跟著我讀
準備
我們一二三
(文章繼續)
(文章結束)
首先
這些寫信徒是誰來的?
這些寫信徒是
法律的老師
寫信徒
他們很認識
舊約
他們認識
和真正了解
舊約
他們就下來
他們就上去
Galilee
上去怎樣?
指責耶穌
是甚麼?
是謊言
指責耶穌是謊言
寫信徒指責耶穌的兩件事
第一件事
是耶穌自己
是被波茲巴擁有
第二件事
是耶穌有能力
耶穌為甚麼有能力
去驅散這些靈魂?
因為祂
是
給予靈魂權力
由魔鬼主子
即是是神自己
波茲巴是誰來的?
波茲巴
下一頁
是誰來的?
是巴爾
是古代的
堅尼亞人的神
如果在舊約讀
那些是
神
在人們的名義上
為巴爾的神
而祈禱
也是一個名字
給神的
那麼
這些徒弟就說
耶穌為甚麼可以驅散這些靈魂?
因為祂自己
是
被魔鬼主子權力
祂自己是被魔鬼主子權力
耶穌就說
這怎麼可能?
一個分裂的房子
不可能站起來
好像國際戰爭一樣
有沒有人看過國際戰爭?
冒險者
有國際戰爭的時候
他們是不是
可以對抗不公平?
對抗敵人?
可以嗎?
他們不能對抗
因為他們在對抗自己
誰是?
鐵甲人隊的
舉起你的手
鐵甲人隊
全部是美國隊長
美國隊長
國際戰爭發生的時候
他們是不是在對抗敵人?
其實不是
他們在對抗自己
耶穌就這樣說
我怎麼可以
被魔鬼主子權力
對抗魔鬼?
魔鬼主子權力對抗魔鬼?
一個分裂的房子
對抗自己
不可能站起來
所以耶穌
就說什麼?
下一頁
寫信的爭論
很有趣
這應該是耶穌
對抗寫信
寫信不合理
耶穌
就是合理
這是我們第一點
第一個比較
我們繼續讀
馬克四書
我們一起讀
1,2,3
沒有人可以進入強人的家
並盜竊他的財物
除非他首先對抗強人
然後他就能盜竊他的家
這個形容
是有一個
很大隻
很強的一個人
在他的家
如果你想打劫他
OK
你想打劫他
你要怎樣?
你要先對抗強人
誰覺得他是強人?
Caleb?
Mark?
CY?
你覺得你是強人?
OK,弱人
開玩笑
這個形容
這個故事
耶穌說的這個故事
你覺得強人是誰?
強人是誰?
誰覺得強人是耶穌?
舉手
誰覺得強人在這個故事
是Satan?
沒有人知道?
再問一次
Jesus 還是Satan?
強人
誰覺得強人是耶穌?
舉手
OK,有人覺得
誰覺得強人是Satan?
舉手
OK
其實呢
在這個故事
強人是誰?
是誰?你覺得
是我?
其實是Satan
OK
Satan
Satan的家是什麼?
Satan的家在哪裡?
在地球
OK
他就是地球的主人
所以Satan是強人
他的家就是地球
OK
他被地球壓下來
那麼耶穌是誰?
耶穌是強人的一方
你會看到下一頁
強人的一方
然後他會大力地打破家
我們看到兩個比較
第一
他就說
他更強
Satan更強
他更有力量
撒旦是有能力的
但是耶穌更強
Jesus更強
他可以強人
第二
Satan擁有地球
但是耶穌呢
One day
He has all authority
And he will take back
What is his own
Jesus is stronger
Jesus has all authority
And he will plunder
我們看Revelation 20
One day Satan will be defeated once and for all
And the devil who deceived them was thrown into the lake of burning sulfur
Where the beast and the false prophet has been thrown
False prophet is the
Antichrist
They will be tormented day and night forever and ever
有一天
耶穌會Fully defeat Satan
Fully defeat Satan
So
We see that Jesus is stronger than Satan
Jesus has all authority
And one day he will take back what is his
And he will make a new heaven and a new earth
There is a last part of this scripture that we need to see
我們繼續讀Mark chapter 4
我們一起讀
1,2,3
I say to you
All sins will be forgiven
Of the children of man
And whatever blasphemes they utter
But whoever blasphemes against the Holy Spirit
Never has forgiveness
But is guilty of eternal sin
For what they were saying
He has an unclean spirit
為什麼
耶穌說什麼
If you blaspheme against the Holy Spirit
You will not be forgiven
為什麼
The scribes
What Jesus was saying here
Is the scribes they knew who Jesus was
They knew Jesus was a man of God
Yet in their heart
Instead of agreeing
That Jesus was a man of God
They chose to say that
The Holy Spirit was a liar
The Holy Spirit is lying
And saying that he has an unclean spirit
So they are speaking against the Holy Spirit
And that is an unforgivable thing
He is saying
The scribes were saying that the Holy Spirit is wrong
The scribes themselves
Had possibly had a feeling
That this is not an unclean spirit
This is a man of God
And yet they chose to say that the Holy Spirit is lying
And when we do that
It is an unforgivable thing
So the last comparison is this
The scribes were not logical
And Jesus is logical
The scribes were not truthful
But Jesus is
Jesus is the truth
The scribes were not logical
They tried to defeat Jesus
Using their non-logic
They tried to cast Jesus as a demon
When in fact he is the Lord of Lords
So finally we see this
Firstly, in terms of spiritual knowledge
Jesus is greater than the scribes
He is logical and he is truthful
In terms of spiritual power
Jesus is greater than Satan
He is stronger and he is more powerful
And he has all authority
And one day he will make a new heaven
And a new earth
So that is why in conclusion
Jesus is Lord over the spiritual realm
Lord over the spiritual realm
So what should our response be?
What should our response be?
Knowing about these demons
The first thing is to beware
Beware of what?
That there is a spiritual realm
Demons do exist
Satan is real
They are powerful
We should beware
Understand that there is a spiritual realm
The second thing we need to do
Is to believe
What do we need to believe?
We need to believe that Jesus is Lord over all things
He is stronger
He has all authority
One day he will make everything new
He will judge the earth
He will throw Satan and the Antichrist into hell
And they will be punished forever and ever
So, first, we should beware
Second, we should believe
The third thing is we need to be equipped
How do we defend ourselves?
We have been given the truth, the Bible
We need to know the truth
The Bible teaches us to know Jesus, to know God
To know what the truth is
Do not be deceived by Satan
He has power
He can deceive us
So we encourage you to be spiritual
To know Jesus, to read the Bible
Prepare ourselves, know the truth
Have the armor of God, the belt of truth
And then also, we need to rely on the Holy Spirit
To help us discern what is right and wrong
我們依賴聖靈
To help us know what is right and wrong
What is from God
What is from the enemy
We need to rely on the Holy Spirit
And how also can we be equipped?
By coming to our church, our community
God has given us this body of Christ
That we can help and prepare each other
When we have Jesus
As the next slide says
When we have Jesus, we have no fear
Because Jesus is Lord over the spiritual realm
Jesus is Lord over the spiritual realm